Teams that are perfectly happy are
rarely performing at their very best
potential. This is David Singleton. He
grew from a junior engineer to a VP at
Google, which is four levels higher than
staff. You grew to a VP at Google. So, I
can't imagine you were still taking on
feature work when you're
>> Funny story.
>> Really?
>> When I was made a director at Google,
they said, "Hey, the secret is
>> later he became the CTO of Stripe and
explained how they hire without leak
code." the industry was still doing a
lot of whiteboard interviews. That's
actually like not a great way of
simulating what it's like to see an
engineer do work.
>> We also chatted about the AI startup he
left Stripe 4. How do you see yourself
out competing big names like OpenAI who
probably have interest in this exact
thing?
>> Uh I'm going to choose to answer this
question differently. So here's the full
episode.
The first thing I want to ask you is how
did you get into programming to begin
with?
>> Like many people, I got into computers
as a kid. A computer came into our
household for my parents' business. Um,
and I ended up teaching myself to code.
I think a lot of kids back then, this is
like the late 80s, early 90s, a lot of
kids were like learning to code to write
computer games. I coded bespoke business
software for my parents' business. I
built them an invoicing system,
but it was actually like really cool.
Um, mostly because I learned that I
could do this like really creative thing
with this piece of technology and I was
always really inquisitive about how
things worked. And then the thing that I
built ended up being pretty impactful to
our family. Um, in that before that my
parents did all of their invoice
tabulation for their tax returns
manually. So my sister and I would
notice that like once a quarter they get
super grumpy and it's because they were
up all night like tabulating their
accounts. And once we built the
invoicing software, you could press a
button and it came out of the printer.
So it kind of showed me that this thing
could have a big impact for people. And
it's been the impact of building
software for people that really kind of
gave me the bug to then go on and study
computer science and get into the
industry. Um but yeah, that's how it all
started.
>> After you graduated from college, I
understand that the first role that you
had was at Symbian. Can you
>> tell me the story about working at
Symbian? Yeah. Well, so first of all,
it's a funny story how I ended up there.
I actually originally planned I'm
originally from Northern Ireland. I
planned to go back there to join a
software company in Belfast, which is my
hometown. Um, but it was an internet
boom company and unfortunately kind of
went under as the internet bust
happened. So there I was in Cambridge in
England. Uh, and I had to find a job at
pretty short notice. Some folks from
Symbian visited uh, and I just thought
these are really lovely people. Um, and
so I decided to apply for the job there.
I was incredibly lucky because uh for
those that don't know it, Symbian built
smartphone, mobile phone operating
system software before smartphones were
a thing. So we're talking here like
2001. Um and I ended up going there
because I like the people. But then as
soon as I arrived, I realized, wow, we
are working on technology that we all
believe and I certainly believed was
going to have a profound impact on how
people used computers at scale. It was
just obvious that it was inevitable that
we're all going to have these little
smart computers in our pockets. But we
were inventing stuff there uh that, you
know, today you and I might take for
granted, but we just really had to
figure out what you could do. I remember
whiteboards where we were drawing what
turnbyturn directions in maps would look
like when there were GPS uh chips in the
handsets, which we knew was coming and
we were trying to figure out what's the
right way to plug that into the
operating system. So super super
fortunate to end up there um and find
that I was super passionate about what
we were doing. I started off as a
software engineer. So I built some core
parts of the Bluetooth stack on the
Symbian OS and also some of the PC
connect uh software. But then the final
couple of years I spent at Symbian I
think were actually pretty formative for
me in terms of what came next. So I went
from being a you know IC software
engineer working in the core to doing
this role that we called technical
consultant. So I was still an individual
contributor software engineer but I was
assigned to teams from handset
manufacturers who were turning the
Symbian OS into actual handsets into
actual products. So Symbian arrived as a
kind of bag of bits and you had to put
your own UI on top and build a whole
bunch of things. It was actually quite a
complex project. Um so I ended up being
the technical lead on the Symphian side
for essentially the same project.
executed again and again and again by
teams at different companies. So I work
with companies like Panasonic in the US,
Samsung in both Korea and China, Nokia
in Finland, etc., etc. And the cool
thing is the the right way for me to
help on each of those projects ended up
being quite different. For one of the
teams, I was helping them set up source
control for the first time. For another
one of the teams, I was helping them
like debug some graphics thing that they
were having problems with. But because I
saw how the culture of a software
engineering team um in different
companies impacted how things got built
really directly very early in my career.
It gave me this like almost like
intellectual pursuit of like wow like
how you organize teams and how you set
them up to have impact can make a
profound difference on what the end
result is. Just to give you a flavor of
that. I'm sure that these companies work
completely differently today. But you
know, Samsung back then um they ran very
very small teams um and uh as I
understand it, they would give multiple
teams essentially the same mission um
same project and then the team that was
finished first uh was the one that
actually got to ship. So imagine the
kind of incentive structure that that
sets up. Whereas at Nokia um it probably
won't surprise you to hear that
everything was actually planned in much
more intricate detail. Things were
definitely much more predictable, but
everything took significantly longer.
And yeah, I just kind of really became a
bit of a geek for thinking not only
about what is this software we're
writing, but how are teams organized to
get it done.
>> Would you say that that role was similar
to the popular role of forward deployed
engineer in the industry today?
>> Yeah, actually it's a great question. I
haven't thought about it that way, but I
think I think that is that is a really
good observation. It was the case that I
and people in the same role were tasked
with not only helping the customers
integrate the thing in their own
product, but also to bring back lots of
insights and questions and so forth from
the customers to inform our future
roadmap at Symbian. Um, and so yeah, I
guess it was um we didn't call it that
back then and uh I think I hadn't even
made the connection until now. But yeah,
it's a it's a pretty interesting model.
For what it's worth, you know, I was
pretty young at that time. I I really
enjoyed it. I got to travel all over the
world. Um, and it was a very rewarding
period of my career, even though I
probably wouldn't want to do that right
now.
>> So, you talked about the the future
companies, and I know we're talking
about Google, we're talking about
Stripe.
>> I'd love to hear the story about how you
got into working at Google.
>> Yeah. So, I was living in London at the
time working for Symbian. Um, and this
was immediately post Google's IPO. Um,
and I guess Google, like we had already
recognized at Symbian realized that
smartphones were going to be very
important for how people accessed
services online. Um, and believe it or
not, London at the time was recognized
globally as like a center of excellence
in the mobile industry because there
were so many people working at companies
like Symbian there. So, Google decided
to open an engineering office. Um, it
had a specific focus on mobile in the
early days. Um, and uh, I guess I
attended a recruiting event uh, and
interviewed. It was a pretty tough
process interviewing at Google back
then. I did some interviews in London. I
flew to California. It was the first
time I'd ever been to California as part
of that interview process. But what I
realized was just through the quality of
people I was meeting, but also the
energy at the company, uh, I was
immediately sure that this is where I
needed to be next in my career. And for
what it's worth, I never really imagined
I ended up staying at Google for nearly
12 years. I never imagined staying that
long. I thought what I was going to do
was go to Google and learn a lot. Learn
about how you built distributed systems
at scale, learn about how um, you know,
the very best engineering was being done
in the industry so I could take it
somewhere else. But I ended up staying
at Google so long because every 18
months or two years I'd pick up my head
and think about what have I been doing
here and realize I've learned a
tremendous amount. So I just keep
staying because I was learning so much.
I've noticed that in a lot of people who
have had a lot of career success and
stay at one place for a while. They
don't stay there out of complacency.
They're constantly actually almost
trying to leave but that place is
treating them so well that they end up
staying rather than you know job
hopping.
>> Yeah. I mean at Google I probably did
six different jobs like you look at them
and say that that is a very different
job with all with very gradual
transitions between them. Um but yeah
the dynamic range of skills that I
learned there was incredibly useful and
incredibly you know diverse. In the very
early days it was just an amazing place
to be. Incredible talent density.
Everyone was really driven to have an
impact and everyone was given a lot of
autonomy. So back then like the 20%
culture at Google was really true. So I
definitely had a thing that my own
manager and team were expecting me to
get done but I was really welcomed to
pick up a lot of other things. Um as
long as I could get the core done um and
I really went to town with that. So I
looked at it as this is my opportunity
to learn and I'm going to go find all
the opportunities to learn as much as I
can. And I think that's actually why I
ended up being uh kind of given more and
more things to do at Google. One example
of that is I was working on I think a
feature for Google Maps for mobile at
the time. This is before Android to be
clear. So I was working on a feature for
Google Maps for mobile. Um and mobile
search was growing pretty rapidly. And
one thing that I noticed was that every
time anyone on a mobile phone would go
to google.com, we would immediately then
redirect them to google.com/m.
And back then, mobile network roundt
trip times were super long, like
multiple seconds, two and a half seconds
maybe to follow one redirect. Uh, and we
were subjecting every mobile user to
that. And I remember talking to my
co-workers and being like, "This is
bonkers, right? We were wasting 2.5
seconds of users time every time they
access this page." And everyone was
like, "Oh, it's kind of too hard to fix
that. It's really complicated. It's in
this kind of front-end infrastructure
that no one really on this team knows
how to work with." I was just like
pretty determined that this didn't make
sense and it's just software so I must
be able to figure it out. And it was
really because I wanted to learn about
how that infrastructure worked and I
went and chased that. Um and eventually
like merged a change in the main Google
web server and did a whole bunch of
stuff on that front-end infrastructure
to remove that redirect. Um and that
ultimately ended up saving I did this
calculation like something like 70 years
of user time every year or something
like that. Um and was pretty impactful.
it I think had a noticeable impact on
usage as well. Um, and you get a real
bug for those things like being able to
just follow your nose to learn, take
agency to do stuff that matters. Um, and
I find that just really fun and a great
environment to be in and to continue to
learn.
>> The thing that motivated you in that
agency that worked out for your career,
was that the perceived impact that you
would have or was that the technical
curiosity?
>> That's a a good question. I I'm sure
that initially early in my career it was
technical curiosity. Um I honestly had
no real sense of just how many people we
were impacting in the work I was doing
at Google and it was a lot but I was
very technically curious and then I
worked with a product manager um a good
friend of mine still called GI and he
then started putting all the product
metrics in terms that everyone could
understand. He's so he's Icelandic and I
remember one day the product we were
working on he said we now have as many
active users as the population of the
country that I come from. Now Iceland is
not a very big country. Um but he just
kept doing that every week. This week we
surpassed the population of Ireland and
this week it was Scotland and the next
week eventually it was like Germany. Um
and that was really amazing because I
just find myself picturing like the
whole population of Iceland using our
product in a day like really amazing. So
I started out with technical curiosity
as the motivator and then it was really
Google that taught me to start thinking
about how many people you could impact
and that has been the real driver for me
behind everything that I've done since.
>> Yeah, that framing is really powerful I
imagine in motivating a team to move
forward towards things that are
impactful. I remember YouTube also had a
very similar thing which was that they
for the longest time they were driving
towards was maybe like a billion uh I
don't know minutes watched per some unit
of time
>> and that unifying goal just everyone's
saying okay billion's a big number I'm
going to you know chase that and so I
could totally see why that was very
motivating for you as an engineer. Yeah,
I think anytime that you're able to lay
out a really clearly defined executable,
so it's possible but audacious goal and
like help everyone rally behind it. I
think teams often do incredible things
to make that happen. Um, and I've been
lucky to experience that, you know, as
an engineer and then later try to use
that kind of tool as a manager and
leader. So yeah, you talked about
management and I understand that you
grew from an IC to a manager quite
quickly and when people think about the
management versus senior engineer fork
in the road, it's not a clear-cut
decision for everyone. So I'm curious
what was the story behind you making
that decision for yourself?
>> Yeah, it's a funny story actually. I was
an IC engineer and was having a blast
and was learning a lot and I think it
was because I was around a lot of
product managers that were really
helping the team see how much impact
they had. I remember I walked into my
manager's office one day and I said,
"Hey Dave," he was called Dave, he still
is. He's a good friend. Hey Dave, I want
to be a product manager. And he kind of
looked at me a scance. He was like,
"Well, if you really want that, we can
figure out how to make it happen, but
you should be an engineering manager."
and he basically pitched me on the idea
that as an engineering manager I'd be
able to feel the same kind of
fulfillment in terms of impact that I
might in a PM role and I'd be able to
continue to do technical work. So Google
at that time had this role which uh was
variously called TLM or Uber tech lead.
Um and he really pitched me on doing
that. He's like you love engineering,
you love writing code, so do this. Um
and so for me that was quite an easy
choice. Um, I mean to be clear, the team
needed more managers at the time, so I'm
sure I was solving a problem for him.
Uh, but I do get a lot of fulfillment
and energy out of helping people
accomplish more together than they might
on their own. And then I was able to
continue being like super in the
details, writing code, producing
designs, and so forth. And then as I
developed in my uh career at Google, I
ended up taking on more and more teams
at the same time. So still managing IC's
but multiple teams at a time and the
management job definitely took over the
vast majority of what you would think of
as normal work time. But something that
was true then at Google was that
everyone was encouraged to use their 20%
time. So um I this was a period of my
life where my wife was working a very
busy job. Um and I just like was super
energized by the work I was doing. So I
spent a good couple years where I was
managing teams during the day and then I
would have my own like real personal
engineering projects uh as soon as folks
started to go home. Uh one of those for
instance was I built the uh the first
version of Google Translate on the
iPhone and that was cool. It gave me a
chance to interact with a whole new
group at Google. Um, and it was some
like hands-on engineering work, real
engineering work with with impact, um,
that helped me kind of continue to
scratch both itches. And I feel very
fortunate to have had that experience.
And if you're someone out there who's
thinking about I love writing code, but
I think I could have a lot of impact as
a manager. Um, I do think if you can
find a place where you can continue to
do both, uh, it can be incredibly
fulfilling. Um, and of course I decided
to work pretty hard during that period,
but I was loving it. Um, and so I think
if you derive a lot of energy from
something, just go at it.
>> Most of the people that I talk to who
tried the TLM role and I asked them, "Do
you recommend it?" They they tell me no.
They they say you're doing two jobs at
the same time and it's difficult to
excel in either one. So what do you say
that? Because it sounds like you're
supportive.
>> Yeah. So I understand that perspective.
The projects I was managing were
different projects from the ones that I
was being an IC on. I think if you're
trying to be an IC on projects that
you're also managing, which by the way
I'm doing right now at the startup and
having a blast, um it can be more
challenging because you have to kind of
continually figure out how to make sure
that you're putting on both hats.
>> If you're working as an IC on a project
that you're also the manager for, it's
very easy to get sucked into your own
personal work and kind of lose a little
bit of track of like what does every
individual in the team also need to be
unblocked? And it just requires constant
a constant like prompt to kind of go
into this different mode. Many years
later um at Stripe I worked with this um
management coach, a guy called Jeff
Lawrence and he had this um analogy he
used which was when you're a leader you
have to continually step onto the
balcony. So like you're on the dance
floor doing stuff in the in the org but
you have to like prompt yourself to step
onto the balcony and then look down at
how everything is working. you know, he
was teaching me that in a completely
different context, but I think that's
actually true for TLMs as well. So, I
think it's a particularly challenging
role to make work well, but I think you
can make it work well, and I've
certainly had a blast doing it. Um, as
long as I think through and try to
create the moments in the week and the
day to to do that step onto the balcony
thing. I mean eventually though you grew
to a VP at Google. So I can't imagine
you were still taking on feature work
when you're, you know, that level of org
leader, right?
>> Funny story
>> really. Um certainly by the time I was a
VP um at Google, I was not I wasn't a
critical contributor in any of the
projects. But something I really believe
pretty deeply and I took this into my
work at Stripe as well is that no matter
how senior you are, the most effective
leaders find some way to experience the
work of the team at what I describe as
like the one foot level, the actual work
of the team. I found an actual tool for
this which I call engineeration uh when
I was at Stripe. But I did this at
Google as well as a VP engineering. I
was running this program called Android
Wear. Um it is the foundation of the
wearables uh platform that is in all of
the Google smartwatches today. And I was
running that almost as like a GM, you
know, product, engineering, business
partnerships, user experience, etc. Uh
marketing, everything. It was great. I
still find it was incredibly valuable to
actually experience the tool chain that
the engineers in my org were working in.
um it just made it much easier for me to
ask smart questions to actually see what
was necessary to unblock them. So
periodically um during that period it
was probably once every
two 3 months I would find a way to go
and do a little project in the codebase.
Um and I think that the the context that
that gave me back then uh made me a much
more effective VP engineering. Um, and
so I still do that today and did that
for my whole career at Stripe.
>> I remember when Elon Musk bought Twitter
and there was this really strong
influence from his side on managers
should code and this push basically what
you're saying and I guess some of the
downstream benefits of it came in. There
was a big debate in the industry on that
thing. And you know when I think about
going deep versus scaling yourself like
the very brainless quick thing I could
think of is you know that IC project
that you might have done like the iPhone
one for instance you could also have
position someone to do that work and
then you go focus on more you know high
lever things. So what's the case against
that? Yeah. So these were two very
different moments in my career. So when
I did the iOS translate app, um I was
still like relatively junior. I think it
was you know first year TLM at Google.
Um so doing a real engineering project
end to end was was I think like quite
appropriate to keep my skills like you
know fully um fully sharp. Um, by the
time I was in these like org leader, you
know, managers of multiple managers kind
of roles, um, it certainly would be
pretty damaging if I was trying to code
the whole time. Just there's so much
work to be done in those jobs to help
the team have the right context, to
unblock things, to have the right
partnerships in place, to, you know,
especially in a large company like
Google, to work across the company so
that folks know what you're up to. That
is the work. Like, that is, you know,
95% of where you need to spend your
time. Um but I do have this like deep
not just belief but like experience that
having carving out a little bit of time
and being quite deliberate about it um
to go and actually work in the same mode
as the teams that ultimately the
managers of managers are running gives
you just this tremendous uh context.
This practice is not like new. uh if you
study manufacturing uh there is uh you
know a practice of managers and senior
leaders going and working one day a year
or something on the factory floor so
they really understand what they're what
they're talking about and I think this
is applying that already known practice
to the software industry maybe I could
just skip forward here a little bit and
share like so how did I do this at
Stripe I would take time at least once a
quarter except maybe the final quarter
of the year which is always pretty busy
to go and join a team for a few days um
and complete a small real project and I
called it engineer occasion um it's a
port manto of engineer and vacation
because it was really just a few days um
and obviously there are a lot of other
things that people expected of me in my
role quite legitimately but I could take
a few days of vacation and it was fine
nobody everything continued so I would
say for these three days think of me
being on vacation if it's a crisis I'll
answer the phone we we'll we'll get
together, we'll sort it out, but if it's
not urgent and can wait a few days, just
don't bother me because I'm doing this
thing. Every single time I would make a
very detailed friction log. Here are all
the things that we ran into that were
frustrating. Um, and that served as
great input for me as CTO there. I was
thinking a lot about how much and where
should we invest in developer
productivity. So like I really kind of
this visceral sense of how things were
going and it also
served as a great resource for me to ask
all of the right questions when it came
to operational reviews and so forth. So
that practice was something that I used
and then you know really encouraged
other uh managers in the organization to
use as well and not everyone did it but
those who did find it incredibly
valuable and I think it's a good
practice especially if you're working at
a large organization and you're thinking
ah I'm getting a little bit out of touch
with what's really going on do an
engineer occasion. So, if I'm
understanding correctly, that first case
on the iOS team, you were hands-on
through and through. You were an
individual contributor, as a manager.
But the latter thing that you're
recommending as an org leader is more of
a educational thing for yourself.
>> It's important to embrace it as an
opportunity to also show what you have
what you've seen to everyone else. It
can give context. I I found that the
reports that I'd write from my
engineeration were useful not only for
me conveying you know some context but
also for a bunch of other managers like
oh that's how that thing works and oh I
kind of had this mental model but I see
that it's like slightly different
especially all of the infrastructure
that we were working on was changing
over time that kind of educational
exercise um is I think the heart of the
value
>> eventually you mentioned you know
transitioning to or leader you still got
involved here and there but ultimately
you weren't hands-on. It's just the
nature of the role. To me, you seem like
an engineer through and through. Were
you ever afraid of losing your technical
edge?
>> The really short answer here is not
really, no. Because um between
opportunities to write bits and pieces
of code um at work um and the ability to
invest my free time in in programming. I
love programming. Like truly, I get I
get into flow state when I'm
programming. And so if I'm not getting a
chance to do a lot of it at work, by the
way, right now I get a lot at work. So I
don't need to do very much in my spare
time. In fact, I don't have spare time.
I just work on the stuff that we're
doing, which is fun. Um, but if I have
spare time and I haven't programmed for
a while, then yeah, I'm going to jump
in. So for instance, I find uh the last
several years I've been doing Advent of
Code in December, it's awesome. Get a
chance to kind of make sure that I'm
keeping some of those skills sharp.
Before we leave the IC versus EM
decision, um, a lot of people in the
audience probably making this decision
for themselves or kind of near it. How
do you think about what's the optimal
way to make that decision?
>> The advice that you mentioned, which is,
hey, being a manager and being an IC are
different jobs, don't try to complete
them together. That does resonate with
me. I've given that advice to many
people. Um, I think if you are
considering becoming a manager, the best
way to do it is not to try to kind of
join it on the side of something you're
doing. Try to find an environment where
you can do that like full-time, really
focus on it. um put your own IC work to
one side so that you can think very
carefully and really pay a lot of
attention to what does it take to make
this team the most productive, the most
happy, the kind of best version of
itself that it can be. When I see people
do it that way, they tend to thrive when
they try to do both at the same time.
Unless it's very carefully structured,
it can be harder. If you find yourself
at a company that is willing to let you
do that on a trial basis and then make
the decision, well, number one, you're
very fortunate because many companies
don't have that, you know, luxury, but
there are larger companies that will
make that possible. And if that option
is on the table for you, I definitely
suggest doing that. There are many
people I've worked with where they've
let me know that they want to go into
management. Um, and often the first
thing I do is actually try to talk them
out of it. It's like, well, why?
Sometimes I I think this has changed a
lot in the industry over the last 5
years, but certainly if you wind the
clock back 10 years ago, I think there
was this kind of real I don't know like
weird incentive structure where everyone
felt like becoming a manager and
managing bigger and bigger teams is kind
of the prize and therefore I should do
that because that's what success looks
like. Um I think luckily a lot of
companies uh companies like Google and
Meta have really cultivated this idea
that the IC career ladder can go all the
way up. Um, and so you don't just have
to have these big teams in order to, you
know, win. But back then, I would see a
lot of folks that wanted to switch into
management because it just felt like the
right thing to do or the way that you
kind of like progress your career. Um,
and it being a a good manager and being
a manager that actually like feels
fulfillment out of the job, it does
require you to actually like take a lot
of um energy and get a lot of energy
from getting more out of other people.
And that's not for everybody. So like
really reflect on whether that's
something that gets you excited and if
it is give it a try. If you're in an
environment where you can try and go
back amazing and if you if you aren't
give it a try and you know um I'm sure
that there are other ways that that
things can go in future.
>> You mentioned at Google and meta there
are these parallel tracks and they can
go equivalently as deep but there are
differences between the roles and
there's probably differences between the
progressions.
Let's say you're someone in the audience
who's hellbent on I just want to go up.
>> What path would you recommend or do you
have any thoughts on that?
>> I'm going to choose to answer this
question differently. So when I was a
kind of like early and mid-career
engineer at Google, they had this like
very clear incentive structure which
was, you know, you start off as a level
two and then you become a level three
and then a level four. And it's great.
It's like awesome. I've been put into a
game and now I know that the next thing
I need to do is figure out how do I get
to the next level. I'll be honest that's
what I did for a little while. Um,
luckily that aligned very nicely with
things that I was getting a lot of
energy from. But the more I have worked
with many many people and talked to them
about their own experiences and even
later in my own career um what I've
realized is you have the the the way to
have the most fulfillment out of your
work is to try and figure out what do
you want out of it. You know is it the
flow state from coding? Uh is it working
on something that's incredibly impactful
to many many people? Is it working with
a team that you have a really strong
bond with? While so many of these
companies that we all work at set up
these kind of obvious games to play,
take a step aside and try and think,
what am I trying to get out of this? And
it might be to take the next step on the
kind of career ladder that's been put in
front of you. Or it might be to do
something quite different. Um, and it
was by the time I came to thinking about
leaving Google that I think I really
figured that out. And I've reflected on
my own work in that way ever since. And
I I I feel very confident saying I feel
significantly more fulfilled for it.
>> I think I mean there's so many things to
optimize for in career. Fulfillment of
course is uh the conventional wisdom and
obviously there's a lot of benefits to
it. I still think there are people who
will chase the carrot even if you gave
them that advice. That's okay because
the carrot for them is the thing that
they want to chase. I think it's just
like make sure you're chasing the right
carrot.
at Google. I understand that you went
from a entry- level IC all the way to VP
of engineering and that's you must have
a very unique perspective because almost
no one gets promoted to to levels of
that uh height. So I wanted to ask you
because you went through levels of
magnitude of management that I wanted to
hear your perspective on the
differences. So
>> I was curious the first step is you know
frontline manager versus manager of
managers when you made that jump what
was your biggest skill gap?
>> So I actually think that my very early
career as a manager at Google I learned
a lot of the wrong lessons. Something
that you can do as a manager of one team
is you can do everything that you
possibly can to make that team happy.
And that is not the same thing as
getting the best impact out of that
team. Um, and it may actually not be the
case that they look back on that time as
the the kind of best time of their
career. And I think that's what I did as
an early manager at Google. I actually
um I won this thing called the great
manager award when I had a a single team
reporting to me. Uh, which was this like
pretty prestigious award inside of
Google. And you know, I'm grateful to
the folks that um put that thing
together because there was a nice
program of investing in those folks. Um,
I don't think I deserved it. The reason
is that award was voted for by the
teams. So whoever whichever team like
gave the most votes to their manager,
that manager got the great manager
award. Um and what I learned later,
especially as I started managing
managers was that those teams that are
perfectly happy are rarely performing at
their very best um potential. Um, in
order to have the biggest impact, it's
really important to like pretty directly
make sure that low performers are being
managed. By the way, you can't make a
whole team happy without making sure
that they feel like they're surrounded
by folks that are all pulling their
weight. But as a manager manager, you
start to realize, oh, here's a manager
in my orbit, you know, in my team who
has a really good sense of what we're
trying to do is really good at like
moving all the distractions out of the
way and actually will push the team a
little bit to fulfill the the most
impact that they can and you know,
here's someone else that is doing what I
used to do. Um, and the answer there for
me was actually go and like help them uh
get more out of the team. And so
as I became a manager of managers, I
think I I stepped onto that balcony I
talked about earlier much more and
reflected on um how is this entire group
of people
essentially configuring themselves in
order to get the most out of everybody.
And then it is also the case that the
tools you have available as a manager of
managers change. So as a as a line
manager, it's like I'm need to have the
right oneto ones, the right onetoone
docs and the right goal set for the team
in order that they, you know, can make
progress. And hopefully you also kind of
want to get into the craft a little bit
with folks to help them. Once you're a
manager of managers, you can start to
think about what are the systems we're
running in this organization um that
will help us achieve our goals best. So
you know, how do we do things like
product reviews? Um uh how is our hiring
process working? you know, only in some
companies can managers managers change
that, but I've been lucky enough to, you
know, be at each stage in a state where
I could do that. Um, and you really
start reflecting on I need to think
about not just how I show up day-to-day,
but what tools and systems I'm putting
in place for the organization. Um, as a
software geek and a distributed systems
geek, I found it quite exciting to think
about the organization I was running as
as if it was a little bit of an
operating system. How do all the things
that we do every day and every week and
every month and every quarter and every
year fit together to help us like get
the most out of everybody? Um, and
that's just like a whole new toolkit
that you don't think about when you're a
line manager.
>> Am I understanding correctly that if a
team is too happy, that's actually a red
flag for you.
>> So, I'm not saying I want anyone to be
unhappy. Um and you know a key trait of
the organizations that I you know aspire
to to try to build is that I'd be very
happy to do any of the jobs in the
organization. I really mean that. Um but
it is the case that I find over time
that when I compare the teams that are
reporting the greatest happiness
um to the teams that are reporting like
pretty happy but I have all this
feedback of things that could go better.
It is usually the case that if I then
grab the same people a year later and
ask them, hey, how was it really? The
folks that were that that were not
perfectly happy and had this like, you
know, desire to change things and were
um put into a position where they
thought a lot about their impact
actually tended to have had the best
time in retrospect. Um, at Stripe, I I
learned about this thing called type two
fun. It's the fun that is you think of
it as some of the best times in your
life when you look back on it, but it's
kind of hard, you know, in the moment.
And I think as managers, certainly for
me as a manager, I want to create a lot
of type two fun for the teams that that
I work with. Doesn't mean it's not going
to be, you know, a good sustainable
experience, but let's look back on it
and think we got a lot done in that
time. Does that make sense?
>> That makes sense. Yeah. And I think that
that's a really interesting I guess
spectrum that you call out in the
happiness of teams. It reminds me also
of there's a similar concept with teams
that are not breaking anything is
probably moving too slow.
>> It's a great
>> you know teams that are breaking.
>> It's a great analogy.
>> You should there should be some downside
other you're too far.
>> That's right. Yeah.
>> You know we talked about frontline
manager versus manager of managers. Now
I'm curious about the step that very few
people ever experience which is you went
through senior management all the way to
VP. What's the difference between you
know your role as a senior manager
versus when you were a VP? I think this
probably takes different forms for
different individuals. Um, for me the
thing that defined the difference
between being a VP at Google and being a
very senior manager was that I took on
responsibility for leading functions
beyond engineering. By the way, my title
was VP engineering, but I I think by
that stage at Google, we we didn't pay a
lot of attention to the exact job family
that you were in. It's all about like
we're trying to get a thing done. What
are what's the full set, you know, set
of skill sets that have to come together
to make this happen? And that does
change your perspective. Certainly for
me it changed my perspective quite a
lot. Much earlier in my career I had
tended to think Google by the way was a
classically like engineering first
company in in those days. I had tended
to think of like well all the other
functions kind of exist to like feed the
engineers to help us all have impact.
Not true by the way. I think if you are
working in an environment where you
don't have the other functions to help
make sure that you're solving the right
problem, you're getting the right user
input, you've got the right business
deals in place to have uh you know the
potential for a lot of impact, you're
going to have much less fun and much
less impact in the world. But I hadn't
really understood that until I uh was
put in the position of leading multiple
functions. It is quite a mental
transition. I think there are much
better engineers than me that work on my
team today and have worked on most of my
teams all the way along. Um, but when
you're managing a function that you have
yourself been part of before, you do
have this like quite visceral
understanding of like how to do the
work, which is valuable. I have
designers who report to me. I can tell
you I am a pretty lousy designer. If you
put me in Figma, I will not do a very
good job. Um, and yet I have to figure
out how to be a good manager and leader
of of those folks. Um, it turns out I
actually like care a lot about design
and can have really good high bandwidth
conversations um about a lot of the
work. But it took a real adjustment for
me to actually feel some confidence in
that when I knew that I would not be
able to jump into any seat in the
organization and perform the job. So
that was for me. By the way, a little
bit of like a personal confidence thing
there as well as here's a whole new set
of problems to solve. But that was for
me the biggest transition in that that
jump in my career.
>> Did you ever consider that engineeration
tool but for the other roles?
>> Yeah. So I've actually done it um at
Stripe. Um I had a team which was part
of the the technology org that built
tools for sales. Super important for uh
a company like that. And I wanted to
understand better how are these tools
being used. So I actually did at one
point do the equivalent I think I called
it a sales occasion. I went and um uh
shadowed a couple of sales people within
the org. Super super useful. I I was
doing that of course mostly to gain
context for how we should prioritize
work on the engineering side. Um but
yeah it's it's a pretty valuable tool. I
wouldn't do it in quite the same way
obviously. So for instance, if you asked
me to do a design occasion, um I think I
would have to do it more as like a kind
of shadow someone than I jump in and do
all the work myself. But it's a useful
tool.
>> In a previous interview, you had
mentioned that communication is
incredibly important for senior
engineering leaders.
>> What are your thoughts on how to get
better at at communication?
>> Uh so there's there's two forms of
communication at least. um writing and
speaking. Um so let's start with
speaking. The number one way to get
better at speaking to large audiences
um is practice. Um I remember very early
in my career being
like really quite nervous um when I had
to present to I think at that time was
like the whole Android or something like
that. And it's pretty hard when you're
nervous to kind of very clearly think
about what you're saying and communicate
it really naturally. Um, and I was very
fortunate to have a super supportive
manager at the time who said, "Yeah,
okay. If you want to get better at this,
we'll just give you more at bats
essentially." It was in London, so they
didn't say that. Um, more more um more
kind of chances to practice this. And I
I got sent along to speak to a whole
auditori
uh Google customers. Um, so I was
working on ads stuff at the time. Uh, I
remember doing one of those in uh, an
office near King's Cross in London and
looking out into the crowd. It was one
of the first I'd done with, you know,
maybe a thousand people in the crowd and
I was to give a live demo and give a
kind of inspirational talk about um,
local ads and it was really scary. Um,
but I did it. There's actually a video
of it on YouTube. Of course, I look back
on that and think about how, you know,
today I probably do a much better job,
but it's getting the reps in is what
what makes that go well. Then there's,
you know, communicating in writing. Uh,
this is something I'm definitely still
learning to do better. Today, I use
Claude a lot um to help with that. But I
think if you can condense the most
important things that you need to convey
into a short clear document, that can be
incredibly valuable because I can talk
to one person and it takes a certain
amount of time. I can talk to a whole
audience of people and maybe you know
30% are really paying attention and you
kind of forget over time. If you get a
really good document out there, people
will pass it to each other. They'll read
it once. they might come back to it
again later. It's an incredibly
leveraged way to communicate at scale.
But I also think you have to do both of
these things. Um I think people like to
listen to folks that they feel like they
have some kind of personal relationship
with and the personal relationship
really only comes from like live
conversations. Um once a really strong
personal relationship has been uh
established then it becomes really uh
easy and scalable to read things um and
kind of take it from there. There are a
lot of people that
speak a lot but I don't think they speak
like you speak. like I I watched you
gave a like a keynote in 2019
uh for Stripe Sessions and you came onto
stage and just immediately within a
second I'm like this guy's confident he
knows what he's saying. So there's
something different about the practice
that you did or you know because there
managers all speak all the time but I've
been to many you know all hands or
people are zoning out. So
>> well I appreciate you saying that. I
mean look I am enthusiastic about what I
do and I think hopefully a little bit of
that kind of comes through in in how I
speak. It really is the case though that
if you had tried to put me on that
Stripe sessions stage in 2012,
you would have had a completely
different conclusion. You would have
thought that guy seems a bit out of his
depth. So it really was the practice
that helped with those things. And I
credit the manager that just said you
need to practice this a lot and I can
see that there's something there so
let's go get it done. One other thing I
want to say in speaking as well is it's
not just about giving these big keynote
presentations. One thing that happens as
a you know relatively senior leader is
you're essentially always on stage as
you walk around the building uh you know
in the office um folks pay a lot of
attention to like how you're doing like
they'll take a lot of their own
confidence in the plans of the company
from the body language of you know the
CTO um I found myself kind of keeping
that in mind a lot um and I'm me uh I
wasn't ever putting on a weird face or
whatever but just that means you know
hallway conversation
or uh this random meeting you're in.
It's another opportunity to remind
people of like what we're doing and why
we're doing it. Um and so kind of using
all of those opportunities to convey uh
an overarching message was something
that I learned over time was was
important and valuable. It's also
important to have some dynamic range in
how you talk about things. Like if
everything's awesome all the time, well,
I mean, everyone knows that everything's
not awesome all the time. So no one's
going to believe you uh when it is
awesome and no one's going to believe
you when it's not. So, uh, but also if
everything's always down in the dumps
and never going to work, then you know,
you're never going to help people get
excited about running over the hill. I
find it was valuable to to take a moment
before I'd open my mouth in any meeting,
whether it was one person or 100 people,
and think, what am I actually trying to
communicate here? And make sure that I'm
using the dynamic range.
>> A lot of engineers who get into
leadership roles, they're tasked with
this um, you know, giving their top of
mind and all hands, etc. And yeah,
>> I think 95% of those, if not more,
everyone's got their laptops out and
it's kind of, you know, most of the
message is falling flat. Do you have any
tips on how that manager can do
storytelling in a way that the org is
actually going to pay attention?
>> Yeah. Number one, prepare. I have made
this mistake many times where I'd be
told, "Oh, just show up and give us a
bit of your top of mind." I'm like,
"Okay, great. I'll show up and I'll give
you top of mind." It's like, oh, uh,
what's on top of my mind right now is
that I'm kind of hungry and, you know,
I'm not going to say that. Um, it's it's
incredibly important to prepare. Think
about what is the most useful um context
for the uh for that audience to to hear
about um and put some thought into it.
You know, they're all spending 15 20
minutes of their time listening to you.
The least you can do is spend 30 minutes
of your time preparing. Um, that's thing
one. I think two is there was a leader
at Google um called Alan Eustace. I
think he was VP of all engineering at
Google when I was a kind of entry- level
engineer who always did this amazing
thing when he would come up to answer
questions or explain things which was
he'd be asked a question and rather than
just answer the question, he always took
the time to take one step back and
explain the context behind the question
and why it might matter. so that folks
who weren't already immediately familiar
with the the problem at hand could
actually both understand what was going
on and could actually learn something
broader from that. I aspire to be like
Alan. I'm certainly not that good, but
um that really I I noticed that and it
really stuck with me and again that's
part of the take a beat. Is it possible
to take a step back and explain the
context behind what you're about to jump
into? It actually always makes it easier
for folks to then uh like pay attention.
Uh certainly if you're talking about
something that the the people have no
idea what it is, they're never going to
pay attention. It also helps with a bit
of a storytelling arc, which is like
first of all, let me tell you why this
matters. Then let me tell you the thing,
maybe there's another detail, and then
let me remind you what I just told you.
Um that's that's another trick
>> for writing. The thing you called out
was condensing the writing. And you
know, you recently wrote this post about
agents, you know, crossing a chasm. And
I scroll to the bottom of it and it
there's this thanks. It says, you know,
Ari Grant, a bunch of, you know, these
people had reviewed it.
>> Yeah.
>> How important is is the people reviewing
your writing in that process of
condensing?
>> Yeah, this is something I learned at
Stripe. Um, I used to write blog posts
and just throw them out onto the
internet and, you know, I get pretty
good feedback about them sometimes. This
is one about a neural network controlled
car that I wrote. Got a lot of coverage.
But I would see people at Stripe writing
really good documents and crediting the
people who'd reviewed them. And I was
like, "Oh, that's interesting." And so I
started doing it. Uh started sending
drafts of um things that I thought were
important to other people. And it
improved the quality of my writing
immensely because of course as an author
of a piece you always have a mental
model of like what am I trying to con
convince someone of or convey what might
they already know and you'll write it
with that in mind. It's actually quite
common that I would share something I've
written with you know a friend or former
co-orker whatever and be completely
blown away by the feedback they give me
in terms of like it would surprise me.
It's like oh I wouldn't have thought you
would have asked that question and then
of course you can go back and kind of
adjust your draft. All right. To be
clear, you don't need to do this for
every email. That would be a waste of
time. But something that you think is um
an important place you're trying to
convey, some important piece of
information, it's incredibly useful to
run it by some people.
>> Before we leave, just general management
practices. I think we talked a little
bit about scaling yourself and you said
it was especially important as a senior
manager and higher. What are those ways
that you think are really high lever
ways to scale yourself aside from
coaching your direct reports? Yeah. So I
alluded to this. Um, one of the tools in
your toolkit as you become like quite
senior is to start thinking about the
how the organization works, the rituals,
the processes. By the way, when I was a
early career engineer, I used to think
that the word process was kind of like a
dirty word. In fact, at Symbian, since
the company doesn't exist anymore, I
feel a little comfortable sharing some
of the stuff that wasn't so good. They
had this thing called a process library.
Um, and if you were doing anything at
the company, you were supposed to go to
the process library and look up the
process and then follow it. I think this
was part of like ISO 90001 certification
or something, which is like this British
um, maybe it's international quality
certification. Anyway, everyone was
supposed to do that. Of course, nobody
did that because you like, well, I know
what I need to get done. I'm like under
a lot of pressure. Got to got to move,
right? Um, but sometimes afterwards,
someone would come along and ask you,
hey, show me the documentation of how
you followed that process. So, you know,
you grab it and fill it out. Um, so I
just thought of pro I didn't I'd never
really heard the word process before and
I thought of process as this kind of
like joke honestly and then I found
myself being you know an organizational
leader and I was like someone told me
David just really think about the
processes in your organ. I was like oh
my god no and then I realized hang on a
second like think from first principles
here what are they actually talking
about and they meant like the rituals
and how we work and how we get stuff
done um and actually like really leaning
into getting those set up right is
incredibly impactful. For instance, one
of the things that um I did with the
help of some folks who reported to me um
at Stripe was set up a set of meetings
um which we called ops review um which
actually kind of nested in the org. So
there was a weekly one that I ran and
looked at kind of the the kind of most
important stuff, but there was a nested
set of them that ran across all of the
engineering teams in the whole company.
And that was a really really valuable
like tool to help the whole company pay
attention to and improve on a whole
bunch of things like reliability and
efficiency that you know otherwise would
have been very hard to get you know
impact on through just talking to your
directs and having it kind of trickle
down. Um so that's the main tool.
>> You mentioned hating processes and I
think that's pretty common among
engineers. How do you decide when the
process is net positive versus net
negative?
>> I think as
someone who is in control of a process
or is like responsible for running it,
your job is to make sure that it it it
only exists as long as it is clearly a
net positive for everyone that that's
you know responsible or kind of
operating within it. And then of course
there's a really interesting
organizational design thing here because
in some companies I'm not talking about
Stripe here. I think we did a really
nice job of it. In some companies, there
will be a person who's responsible for
like executing and overseeing the
process that is not actually the person
that kind of cared about it existing in
the first place or even like brought it
in to solve a particular problem. But
because it's their thing and it's kind
of their job, it's very hard for them to
say is it actually fit for purpose. Um
but then you know running large
organizations our jobs are like let's
make sure that we just don't do that.
Um, there's always tons of work for
everyone to do. So, no one should feel
like they're boxed into continuing a
thing for no particular reason.
>> But how do you prevent that? If you
know, let's say you're, you know, you're
the VP or you're the manager and you
say, "Okay, we need a
>> we need a SEV review process." And you
go to some tech lead and you say, "Hey,
this is your thing." Now,
>> I can tell you worked at Meta because
you call them SES.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah. Sees, incidents, it's all the same
thing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, you know, that person
that was just handed this thing top
down, they're unlikely to be passionate
about it and really think critically
about this is net positive. But how did
you do that?
>> I know I think it's possible to build
teams of program managers that are
really passionate about the why behind
what they're doing. Um, uh, the program
management group was something that I
helped set up at Stripe and I I feel
like pretty confident saying that the
vast majority of folks there were like
really
just making sure that we were doing the
right thing. Um, and very kind of
focused on impact for Stripe's users. A
lot of that, by the way, comes from
company culture. Um, so Stripe has a set
of operating principles and the first
one of those is users first. So it's
everyone's always looking through the
work they're doing to say why does this
matter? Um and that's something I think
was very precious is very precious there
and I think you know makes sense for I
certainly bring that mentality to what
I'm doing at this company as well.
>> Makes sense. Yeah, I could see the
culture of the people you are delegating
to is important but also probably how
you delegate I imagine is important like
if you gave the context behind why it's
impactful.
>> Yeah, that's a that's a good
observation. If you if you tell someone
do this, well, what else can they do but
do that? If you tell them, here's the
problem we're trying to solve and I
think that we should probably do this.
You go do it and please take agency in
making sure that we're really solving
the real problem, you get completely
different outcomes.
>> One topic that I want to touch on and
this is something that actually Philip
mentioned um specifically which is that
you know Philip is there was another
podcast that I did. He was the site lead
for Facebook at London and he said
>> who did he talk to that gave the best
advice on how to start that site? It was
David Singleton. It was you.
>> Wow.
>> And so uh you know he's he said you had
a track record of doing it and you had
learned about doing that at Google. And
at the same time I imagine there's a lot
of AI companies today that probably
started in San Francisco. They're
probably thinking about scaling up. How
do you get a remote location to carry
the right culture so that it's
successful?
>> Yeah. Well, so Philillip Sue was the
Facebook London engineering site leader
and I was the Google London engineering
site leader at the same time. And we of
course found ourselves kind of in this
fierce battle for talent. Like the
number of times that we both had offers
with candidates and we would realize,
well, we've both been talking to this
person was was a lot. Eventually,
actually, Philip reached out to me and
he's like, "Hey, seems like we should
probably talk uh which was amazing and I
really respect that." By the way, one
thing I love about um Silicon Valley,
which I think is kind of, yes, it exists
right here in literal Silicon Valley,
but also it's kind of a state of mind
of, you know, these ambitious tech
companies, um is the idea that even some
of the fiercest competitors, folks will
help each other um in the craft. Um and
that's kind of what Philip and I were
doing back then. And I think we actually
were genuinely able to help like raise
the bar for engineering in general in
London. But to get back to your actual
question like what's the right way to
set up these effective remote sites,
there's a couple of different things. Um
I have had a lot of experience obviously
of running a site that was quite far
from headquarters. Um so Google's
headquarters were in Mountain View. I
was running this site in London. Um that
distance means it's a lot of time zones
away. So the overlap during the day um
is is very small. So you have to think
about that quite carefully. Um when I
was at Stripe, we had a very vibrant
engineering site. So I was based in San
Francisco. We had a very vibrant
engineering site in Seattle. Completely
different setup because it's in the same
time zone and therefore you can do
different things. So I'm going to start
with the you're quite far away. So in
that setup, it's important to think
about how can we enable the team that
are on the ground in London to actually
be able to unblock themselves the very
most and run as autonomously as possible
so that they need to use that little,
you know, one hour overlap in the day uh
with the folks in California for as few
things as possible because then they're
just going to be able to make more
progress. So what I uh really kind of
like pushed very hard on when we were
doing that was that every team in London
engineering had to have a clear and
complete mission meaning they they knew
what they were doing at a very high
level like this is the goal and they
were given a lot of autonomy and then
they were given like all of the
equipment to go off and execute that
pretty autonomously. Um, and that means
that, you know, for eight hours of the
day when Mountain View is not around,
everyone's just cranking along and then,
you know, a few things come up that you
need to reach out to another team for,
you can solve them in a little time
overlap. Um, the worst way to set up a
team like that would be to have half the
team in Mountain View and half the team
in London because then you you come up
with, you know, a hundred things every
day where two people need to kind of
have a conversation to unblock it and
there's so many of them that you can't
make progress in that little time window
and progress grinds to a halt. So for
for those teams that's that's the right
setup. The other thing that I realized
was oftent times so the the site the
engineering site lead for Google London
I think two before me uh one of the
things that I noticed was he didn't
spend very long in London. I remember
asking him so I was like a relatively
junior engineer. I was like hey Shannon
what why are you never here? He's like,
"Hey, you have to understand the best
thing I can do for London is be in
Mountain View and be kind of like
creating like good personal
relationships with all the people whose
work, you know, we are part of um make
sure they know what we're all up to and
then bring a lot of context back here um
to uh to to enable us all to operate
very autonomously. Um and he was right.
Um so, uh I really appreciated what he
did for us all. And then I tried to do
the same thing um you know later when
when I was you know in the other uh
position which was I would travel a lot
to California so everyone else didn't
have to. They could if they wanted to. I
mean this was different era where where
that was always possible at Google. And
you know a big part of that job was just
like make sure the team is visible. make
sure the capabilities of the team are
very clear so that folks understand if I
need to
implement some like mobile browser thing
there's actually a team of experts at
the Google London or who used to work on
the webkit project or whatever right so
like just making sure that context is
shared um so that's the best way to set
up sites like that um I think the other
thing that I would say is every
effective remote site that I've worked
with or helped set up or whatever
always had a little bit of its own
culture. Um it's useful to have a sense
of identity because it creates an
opportunity then for folks to say ah we
have a sense of identity so we can rally
around this cause which means that we
will actually spend energy to think
about how can we help make this better
right when you identify with like being
part of a clan you think about how to
make sure that this set of people have a
great experience and if you don't have
that the little pieces of friction that
people run into maybe don't feel like
they ladder up to something worth
addressing whereas when there is a sense
of identity it's actually worth leaning
into and that makes the whole team much
more productive. However, it is not a
good idea to have a radically different
culture from the company that you are
part of because the whole point is
everyone's part of that company and if
you start feeling like everyone on the
other side of the ocean is bozo, you're
never going to have a good time at the
work. So the trick is like have enough
of a identity that folks think about
collectively helping each other and make
sure that that identity is rooted in the
culture of the whole company because
that's what everyone is there for. Uh so
some those are some of the things I
talked to talked with uh Philip about
back then.
>> And and when you say culture, you don't
just mean Google. You mean Google London
like your clan like we made t-shirts. We
had
>> uh logos that we put on our laptops and
so forth and we would get together and
talk about what's the kind of work that
this site's really good at. Um what
would we like to see more of? And then I
could make sure that when I was spending
time in California that I was talking to
folks about that to see if we could
create those opportunities.
>> And if I'm understanding correctly, the
earlier part was um you know, the
further away the time zones are,
>> the more independently you'd want each
site to be able to execute.
>> That's right.
>> You know, when COVID happened, I think
there was this big move towards uh
remote being more and more acceptable of
a collaboration model. But now that
you're you're starting your own company
and when you think about teams in this
postcoid environment, which one do you
think is optimal? Do you think it's you
know a team purely in person is better?
Do you think full remote is best? Is
hybrid best? What are your thoughts on
that?
>> Yeah, so at Stripe we had a remote hub
well before co. So we we really
recognized that there is amazing
technical talent everywhere. I mean
certainly like all across the US there
are amazing engineers that are not in
San Francisco or New York or Seattle. Um
and that there is a company we were
missing out if we didn't find a way to
have great opportunities for those folks
to contribute to our mission. Um and so
we put a lot of thought into like what
does it take to make a remote team
really effective. Um, one of those
things is document-based communication
decision-making culture is incredibly
valuable. So, um, we would work pretty
hard to make sure that conversations
that would happen between individuals on
the same team if they happened to be on
a video call or happen to run into each
other in person got written up for the
rest of the team. So, they could they
weren't left out of the conversation,
they could follow along. Um and then any
critical decisions came with a dock
which meant that uh yes it's slightly
slower to make any given decision. Not
always actually because the deliberation
you put to put it in writing is often
like a big part of what makes more
effective decisions in the first place
but because every decision was happening
in a document everyone had a chance to
understand the context contribute their
ideas follow along and then kind of more
bought into the decisions once they
happened. So those are the most
important things I think to make remote
teams work well and if you do them
remote teams can work very well. Um the
other thing that I think is important is
there is no substitute for spending time
together in person to build up like a
personal rapport. But you don't have to
spend every single day in person
together in order to make that happen.
Um, I bet if you and I, you know, went
out for a drink and had, uh, a chat
about all kinds of things, you know,
what we like to do in the weekends and
so forth, that we come away feeling like
significantly more bonded and able to do
good work together than if we'd never
spoken to each other before. And if you
do that on a cadence, could be every six
months, um, teams can then be incredibly
effective, um, even when they're not
together. So, all of these things are
worth doing to make remote teams
effective. And for certain companies and
certain teams in certain circumstances,
I think remote can be, you know, almost
as effective as if you're all just
jamming in one spot together. I do
personally believe though that the very
best is if you're actually all jamming
in one spot together. So, uh, I've
started a new company. We're very small
right now. Uh, maybe we'll talk more
about it in a little bit, but we are all
um here together in San Francisco. Um,
and for this stage of the company, I'm,
you know, excited that that's the right
model. Um, as the company grows, I'm
sure we will revisit that because there
are amazing people that won't be able to
come and join us to work together in San
Francisco. Um, so I I think it's a
balance. I think it is very hard to
build a huge company today where you
just don't decide to lean into how do we
make sure that distributed which is like
different offices around the world and
remote which is um folks that are not
necessarily able to get in the same room
together uh work works well um and so
it's just like something that in our
industry we all have to get used to and
kind of lean into. Coming to the end of
your time at Google, I saw that you know
after you were promoted to a VP, you
remained in that role for two years and
five months. And my question to you is
what was keeping you in that role for
that long if I I don't even know what
further looks like or what was keeping
at that time.
>> Yeah. Uh and honestly, I don't even know
what further would have looked like
there. Um but the short answer is
unfinished business. So I think Google
made me a VP not long after we'd shipped
the first version of Android Wear and we
had a bunch of like really exciting
plans and projects that we had already
kind of I had already kind of kicked off
with a bunch of handset watch
manufacturers and I was just like really
excited to see those over the line. So
that that's what kind of kept me there.
Um it's also the case that at that stage
I definitely felt like I was continuing
to learn a lot and I mentioned earlier
part of my whole philosophy for why stay
at somewhere like that for so long is
always be learning. Um and I was still
learning a lot. Uh I think I was the
first time I was managing some of the
new functions that we talked about
earlier. So it was awesome. Um I will
say then so you could easily ask the
question why did you decide to leave
Google? There came a year, I guess it
was about two years after the moment I
mention where I realized um I was very
happy um and I I so much respect and and
and appreciation for everything that
that company did for me. Um, I was very
happy, but I realized if you think about
if I think about the last year at this
company,
what I've done was exactly the same as
the year before when you could change
the code names of all the projects, but
it was essentially like turn the crank
on the same thing again. And I realized
I haven't learned very much and I'm here
to learn. So, what's going on? So, that
was the thing that was kind of the
wakeup call. And then also, I happened
to end up having some conversations with
a good friend, it was actually Philip
Sue, uh, about the possibility of maybe
starting a company together. and I
realized well that would be an amazing
learning experience. So that kind of
shook me into the mode of like this is
probably the time that I need to think
about making the next move in my career.
>> That's so interesting because I mean now
that I have um you know more of the
context actually you and Philip were not
not enemies but you know kind of
>> we're definitely in a in a tussle for
the best talent in in London. It's just
so interesting that actually that's the
number one person you were thinking
about banding together with for, you
know, starting a new venture.
>> Well, I guess we, you know, found that
we had a lot of mutual respect for each
other. Um, and those are kind of some of
the best, uh, relationships to form in
business. Uh, I I feel very privileged
to have been able to uh to bond with
someone that I was sometimes on the
other side of the table from. So you
mentioned wanting to start a venture
after Google and I saw in the the post
that you wrote actually leaving Stripe
that a company is the the thing that you
were considering doing before you got
into Stripe. So I'm curious what was the
company idea? What's the story there?
>> Yeah. So I mean I already mentioned that
Philip and I uh kind of bonded and we we
were talking about the idea of starting
a company. We had what I think is a
pretty cool idea. I think it's still a
cool idea. If someone out there wants to
build this company, uh, give me a call.
>> Would you fund it if someone is trying
to start it?
>> Sure. Uh, send me a note. Um, at the
time we saw kind of the rise of the gig
economy, you know, the Ubers and lifts
of the world. And I actually had like
this little side project where I was
making these journals and wanted to sell
them. And I find that in order to do
that side project, I needed legal help
and I needed a graphic designer. And it
it was quite challenging to find those
folks. There were some new uh platforms
like Fiverr where you could you could
get some help. And I actually used that
for some graphic design. But I realized,
hey, with this trend towards gig work,
it would be really awesome if folks
could who were, you know, in more
professional um job families could
actually take advantage of this trend,
but also benefit from some of the
stability uh benefits packages and so
forth of actually working for a company.
So the idea was uh essentially like make
it possible to have fractional uh folks
in those you know legal graphic design
kind of job families that you could
recruit as a company on a platform. Um
they'd be employed by uh our firm and we
would invest in their professional
development. So a lot of the stuff that
we've talked about before um and then
they would be you know able to benefit
from lots of diverse work and also the
career development that you would get if
you were working for you know an
in-house firm. uh and we were we're
planning to build that platform. Um as
it happened uh we ended up not starting
a company at that stage um because I
ended up uh well complicated personal
things we decided that it wasn't
immediately the right moment but also I
ended up um as part of that spending
time talking to the folks at Stripe.
What I realized as soon as I spent time
with folks at Stripe was
that company at that time had this still
does has this incredible mission. Their
mission is to increase the GDP of the
internet. It really is literally about
helping entrepreneurs start companies
and scale companies to create jobs um to
enable people to move money in ways that
they haven't been able to before. Um and
that really deeply resonated with me. Uh
remember that I got into software in the
first place by building an enterprise or
you know very small company uh invoicing
system. I realized that what Stripe does
is really important in the world. And
then to my surprise um a lot of what
they needed back then to scale the
company was things that I'd done before.
Like for instance I'd run the London
engineering office uh at Google and we
were looking to open engineering offices
around the world at that time.
uh I had uh a lot of experience in
building new products at Google um and
we wanted to do some of that as well. So
I really very quickly fell in love with
correctly fell in love with both the
mission at Stripe and felt really kind
of drawn and and to something where I
thought that I could do something
profound for you know a good number of
years and uh so I I joined and it was
awesome. In the post, it almost sounds
like you went to them for for advice on
starting the company. Like that was
>> So, how when did you realize the
conversation was turning towards they're
recruiting you?
>> I I did first reach out for advice. Um,
>> by the way, someone once told me,
"Anytime you want money, ask for advice.
And anytime you want advice, ask for
money." And at the time, I was like,
"That's such a cynical view." And then
so many times since it's kind of come
back to me like oh that was actually
pretty good advice. So I did reach out
for advice on how to build something.
Stripe has this product called connect
which is um it powers these two-sided
marketplaces. So it was clearly
something that we would have wanted to
use to build this company and I didn't
know that much about the space. So I
thought if I reach out to uh to folks at
Stripe I'm going to be able to learn a
ton and you know they'll give me some
tips and maybe they might even invest or
something. That's why I reached out. Uh
the first conversation was lots of
advice and was super valuable which I
appreciated. Um but Patrick uh who's
co-founder and CEO there said, "Hey, and
I'm going to be in town soon, so let's
get together." And again, I thought we
were talking about advice. Um but from
the very beginning of that conversation,
I I presume he was approaching it as a
hiring conversation. Uh I was just
learning so much about Stripe and felt
really, as I said, drawn to the mission.
um that it became immediately obvious to
me that this was the next place that I
wanted to have the next chapter of my
career. And look, since I since then, I
have hired a bunch of um you know,
senior execs. Um and it really is a very
to to to be able to find and attract and
then, you know, make sure that they're a
good fit, the the very best senior
people, it's a very custom process. Um
and you know, it's important to have it
is important to have a systematic
approach. Um, but for almost every
person that you'll end up hiring that
that will be a good fit, they're going
to be doing something already that they
probably are like super committed to and
having fun at. Um, and you need to find
the right way to identify them, get on
their radar, start out with an advice
conversation,
um, and then help them see the
opportunity. And then I also think it's
incredibly important to like vet along
the way. Like make sure that this person
is actually uh really going to
supercharge the team. There's a real art
transitioning from the hey getting to
know you conversation to the let's
figure out if this could actually be a
fit conversation and it's a lot of fun.
Um, so I understand you you took the
role as head of engineering at Stripe at
the time and then later you grew to a
CTO and that kind of promotion is um
again probably very bespoke. So what is
the story behind getting promoted from a
head of engineering to CTO?
>> So I mean in actual fact one thing that
I did not care about very much when
joining Stripe was my title. I was
joining the leadership team like the the
kind of core leadership team of the
company and that was important to me
because that was where I felt like if we
were going to get done the things that
the company needed done that that was
the right spot to be. So that was the
most important thing for me was you know
am I landing in a spot where I can
actually help and uh have enough agency
to to make things happen. Um so I don't
think we were ever particularly formal
about what the job really was. Later we
decided that it made sense to give the
job a title of CTO. I think that was
mostly in view of it being helpful to
the company to signal that, you know, I
was in that spot, someone worth
listening to. That's right around the
time that I started running a lot of
these companywide processes I talked
about earlier. Um, it was also super
valuable for helping me engage with
customers and folks outside of the
company. Um, so it's a pretty natural
onboarding. You know, pay attention to
internal stuff first. Once you've kind
of got your arms around that and what's
the business, any senior role, no matter
whether it's engineering, design,
product, um, it's really valuable to be
uh, able to talk to folks outside of the
organization, um, customers, uh,
partners and so forth. And that's where
these titles kind of actually start to
matter. So I really like that kind of a
culture where we're not necessarily
listened to because we have a title. And
that's certainly the culture at Stripe
and it's the culture I would seek to
build and it's this culture I seek to
build here as well. But it's also the
case that when you think about
interfacing with the rest of the world,
this can matter.
>> Definitely. And I' I've heard a similar
opinion of um you know at a large
company the organizations within the
company are almost strangers as well. So
you know it's helpful when the director
is reaching out as opposed to this
person in engineering is reaching out
that you know they'll get alignment and
stuff like that.
>> It makes sense. I mean at one point I'm
rewinding back to Google now. Um at one
point when I was made a director at
Google they sent uh all the new
directors off on a training course. Um
and they said, "Hey, the secret is I
don't know if this was true or not, but
the secret is um it's really directors
that run this company because they were
it was the spot in the organization
where all of the kind of detailed plans
were being transferred between each
other. Um and knowing that cohort was
incredibly valuable. Um and I think
there's something to that. So you have
to think about your org design and like
who does what and having some set of
people and different scale of
organization is going to have you know
different forms having some uh network
of people that are making sure there's
like really high fidelity of context
being transferred is incredibly valuable
and at Google at that time it was
directors.
>> You mentioned org design and as a CTO I
imagine that was something that you
thought about a lot. I see all these
famous engineering cultures, you know,
Facebook has its own thing with, you
know, move fast and break things and all
of these principles. Um, similarly,
Google has its own principles. Amazon
has its own principles. I thought it'd
be interesting to hear your take on
which big tech company's engineering
culture you thought is most
well-designed and maybe, you know, less
well-designed.
>> Yeah. Well, I'm at a bit of a
disadvantage here because I've only
worked at Google among the big um the
big engineering companies and I kind of
know some of the others by reputation.
The culture of Google which I joined was
phenomenal. It was a place where um
everyone was there to do big things. Um
there was the ability and the
encouragement to try to have a lot of
impact. The everyone was given a lot of
agency. The one thing I would say is it
did not I don't think it was very
deliberately designed. I think it was um
uh to be clear it wasn't it wasn't total
chaos um you know there was an org
structure uh but I think it grew up
mostly organically or at least in large
part organically um and by contrast I
think there are companies that have been
much more deliberate about the structure
they put in place comes immediately to
mind um and so as we were designing um a
lot of the both org structure and ways
of working as we scaled Stripe um I
tended to look at companies like Amazon
who'd been very deliberate in their
design for for inspiration. Very
fortunate to have been able to talk to a
lot of senior leaders there um and and
get their tips. In fact, the the ops
review that I mentioned earlier that um
uh we ran at Stripe and continues to run
at Stripe uh was very much modeled off
of the Amazon one. Um uh Charlie Bell
was very kind to, you know, spend I
think a nice lunch with me and run me
through exactly how it worked there. Um
and we tried to take the good bits of
that that were applicable to the the
size and culture of Stripe and apply
them. So um Amazon is definitely the the
company with the very systematic org and
operational design that over time I've
taken uh a lot of uh inspiration from
even though I've never worked there. I
actually joke I joked with a friend
recently. I was like, you know, I would
love to work at each of these companies
for one project just to experience what
it's like. So, you know, I love the
products that Apple builds, but they
famously have this kind of like, you
know, not very transparent within the
company culture. It obviously works for
them. Uh, I think they're also very
deliberate about what their uh org
structure is. There's this thing called
Apple University. Everyone who joins
learns how to work in the Apple way.
That's really cool. I'd love to
experience it to see like what could I
take from that. And that reminds me of
that time all the way back at the start
of my career where I was working with
all these different mobile handset
manufacturers and realized there are so
many different ways to accomplish the
same ends. And I'd love to be able to
kind of choose from the smores board.
But unfortunately I've only worked at
one big company and I've only really
gone deep with leaders um at one other.
>> When I look at Stripe's operating
principles, I do see the Amazon
influence specifically in it's users
first and at Amazon it's customer
obsession. Mhm.
>> I think those are kind of similar in my
mind.
>> I think that's right. Um, you know,
users first is the idea that everything
that folks do at Stripe is really
focused on understanding why it matters
to the user. And that's that's a real
maxim that I live by as well. You know,
think through like why are we doing what
we're doing? What's the ultimate the
ultimate end? Another one of Stripe's
operating principles. And by the way,
just folks may not be familiar with
this, operating principles are a little
bit different from values. So this is
something I really respect about the
early Stripe team. Um, once they had
found product market fit in their core,
which is, you know, the payment
infrastructure for early stage
businesses, they do much more now, but
once they find that early stage product
market fit, they took a little step
aside and thought about what is it about
how we're working um that makes us most
effective. And so Stripes operating
principles, they're not abstract.
They're like very concrete and they are
distilled from the behaviors of the most
effective Stripes. That means they've
also been mutable over time. They
revisit them periodically, not very
often because, you know, they're pretty
stable, but, you know, periodically
they'll revisit and make sure they're
still fit for purpose. One of Stripe's
operating principles that really
motivated me and sticks with me and is
something that I, you know, take forward
is being meticulous in your craft. Um so
that means you know taking pride in how
well things are done for the sake of how
well they're done. So you know making
sure that engineering systems are
designed well making sure that we can
offer reliable services to users. Um
actually taking the time to polish the
edges a little bit. Um taking the time
to take a blog post and get some
external people to review it before you
publish it. That that's kind of all
being meticulous. The thing that's
interesting about that is a lot of
people will you can look at that and say
h does it make any sense like surely
just like focus on the cold hard
numbers. It's been my experience that
there is something that is hard to
quantify that actually has a very
dramatic impact on how how well products
and services that you offer are
perceived because you take that time to
be meticulous in your craft. Um, I
couldn't tell you the number of times
that I would meet a Stripe customer,
very large company that had started on
Stripe when they were much smaller. Um,
and the person I would be talking to was
often the CTO and they'd say, "Hey, I
just got to tell you like I was the one
that did the Stripe integration back in
the day." And you know what? I was so
inspired by the error messages on Stripe
uh that I kind of brought some of that
energy into our own culture. Um, and at
Stripe, if you use the API instead of
like, you know, if you call most APIs
and the resource you're looking for is
not find, it'll just give you a 404 not
found, you're stuck. Whereas, um, with
the Stripe API, uh, they have this thing
called test mode. And oftent times you
have to like switch your integration
from test mode to prod mode, and that's
often times where something will be not
found. They paid attention to the fact
that this went this was a piece of
friction for a lot of users. And if you
request a resource from the other mode,
instead of just a straight up 404, which
is obviously what every engineer would
implement as a first cut, it actually
takes the time to run some extra code
and say, "Hey, not found, but an object
with that ID exists in the other mode."
And that's the kind of thing that's like
meticulous in your craft and people
remember it. Um, and so it it ends up
being incredibly valuable. Um and so all
of this is just to say that being
deliberate about operating principles,
the ways of working that have brought
you where you are um you know when you
have any any any form of success is
incredibly useful.
>> I'm curious depending on the stage of
the company I could see people thinking
that um you know it might be too early
to be thinking about those things and
maybe go more with that less intentional
Google approach that you were talking
about. How do you see that like with the
stage of the company? When do you start
thinking about we need to scale this
culture?
>> Yeah, that's a good question. Uh I'm
building a very early stage company
right now. Um I think it matters to care
about culture from day one. Um, so me
and my co-founders, literally what we
did, I think literally the day that we
incorporated the company was we actually
went out for uh a drink and spent some
time writing down uh what we think our
values are as we build this company. And
that's been useful. Uh we've certainly
been paying attention to that as we
think about people that we're hiring and
the ways that we're running things and
so forth. Um it's also the case that
running an early stage company is an
exercise in uh being smacked in the face
quite often like you know the world will
surprise you and so uh it's important to
have values that help you know where you
might want to compromise and where not.
Um now at the same time I think it would
be way too early for us right now to
kind of spin up a you know every week
we're going to think about what we can
do that contributes to the company
culture. It needs to be kind of more
organic at this stage. But I do think
it's something that obviously I've
worked in much later stage companies as
well. I think it's something that you do
have to be very intentional about all
the way through because fundamentally
companies are just large groups of
people unless you do something to bring
large groups of people together and kind
of give them a shared sense of purpose
and alignment. Uh naturally entropy will
just take over. And so if you don't
invest in culture you almost by
definition will not have a culture. Um
and of course there are all these quotes
like culture uh culture eats uh
execution for breakfast something like
that. I think it's true if you find
yourself in an organization that is very
intentional about how it works you just
mentioned Stripe Amazon they tend to be
very effective um and
you know some of the companies I worked
at very early in my career uh were not
intentional about this um and have not
lasted so I think it matters. How do you
concretely as an engineering leader
enforce culture?
>> So I think there are basically two ways.
Um one is it's important to just be an
amazing exemplar of the culture in the
first place but it also it can't you
can't just kind of make that up like it
has to be authentic. So it is first of
all important like work at a place where
the culture is actually a culture that
you really identify with. Um and then
like ooze it out of every pore. Um and
that really helps. I I genuinely was at
Stripe because I really cared about the
mission. I really cared about users. I
really cared about helping these
businesses uh be able to start and scale
in ways that they they otherwise would
not. Um I also like really cared about
us being able to be meticulous in our
craft. So, and all the other operating
principles. So, it was very hard for me
not to just like show up using the
culture. And I think if I'd find myself
in a in a in an environment where the
values were not aligned with my personal
values, I probably wouldn't have been
able to do that and I probably would not
have stayed so long. So that's thing one
like just you have to live it yourself
and like be the best exemplar.
This is a quote from someone it's well
known but I remember someone you know on
my team told me this once which is like
culture is the behaviors you accept
which sounded really weird to me. Um but
the point is you as in you will have the
culture that is the behaviors that you
accept. So um again I kind of first
heard that I was like that's a pretty
pessimistic way of looking at it but
actually it kind of resonated with me
and it's true. So if you see someone do
something that is clearly not in line
with the culture. If anyone else sees
you see that happen and not kind of talk
about it or call it out that suddenly is
the culture that you're going to have
across the org. So you kind of have to
constantly in as you know pleasant and
upbeat a way as possible be a little bit
of like the police in the culture. This
is a random story but I remember seeing
a senior leader once walk up the stairs
in the office and someone had spilled a
whole bunch of like some drink over the
floor and then they just walked on. Um,
and the culture that we had at that
company, uh, was that, you know, we
really all treated all of our resources
like our own and we cared about all the
other people. And I saw that person
stop, go to the kitchen and clean up the
spill. And they clearly had way more
important things to do that day. But
what were they, A whole bunch of people
saw it, probably not that many, but man,
did that story go around. What were they
signaling? it is worth my time to do
this thing that someone else walked by.
So that behavior of like me making a
mess and not cleaning up is not okay. Um
and I think that really matters
>> with the operating principle for
instance the uh being meticulous with
your craft. You're saying maybe you see
some new UI that's built or some new
project. It's not meticulous. It's
rushed. You as an engineering leader
would in a respectful way call it out. I
would definitely try to as much as I
possibly could. At Stripe, I I
personally did this in a couple
different ways. Uh we introduced a
milling list. It got kind of hard to
find the right component uh to uh file
bugs against in the the bug filing
system. So, we made it super easy for
anyone to report bugs. Um and then a lot
of people would subscribe to that
mailing list so they'd see what folks
were um complaining about. And I just
made it a real kind of ritual that if I
saw things that were not kind of at that
bar, I'd send them there. I'd try to be
as supportive as possible and kind of
suggest how to do it differently.
Sometimes I'd even like, you know, if it
was like a copy change, I'd say, "Here's
maybe the change we could make to make
it as easy as possible." But that is a
good way to kind of be clear about, you
know, what the bar might be. Much later,
um, we set up a system of like actually
we called it walk the store. We'd
actually like use the product in some
companywide meetings. Sometimes it was
me, sometimes it was other people in to
be clear, not in a calling people out
way, but in a kind of very supportive
like this is what we're trying to aspire
to kind of a way to help convey that. So
yeah, that's a that's a good good
example.
>> So this walk the store thing, if I
understand correctly, you are in an all
hands
>> dog fooding the product publicly and if
there's a problem, you would
>> exactly that.
>> Exactly. That could be nerve-wracking.
>> Yeah. Uh some another practice which we
use um here at this company and you know
I learned at Stripe is the idea of
friction logging. So one of the things
that I think any senior leader can do or
anyone can do but you know I certainly
found very effective was to make sure
that I was using the product. Um a lot
of us probably work on products that
it's not super easy for us to use every
day. Maybe you're working a piece of
infrastructure, your user is like
another team at the company. But finding
some time in every week or month or
every six weeks to like actually put on
a different hat, your user's hat, and go
through the process of using your
product and write a friction log, which
is like everything that you ran into
that was a little bit frustrating or a
little bit weird. Um, and then use those
to inform your team's priorities. That's
a really valuable tool. At this company,
Dev Agents, we're building a platform
for uh for AI agents, for consumers, but
there's also a developer and creator
experience, and we go through a process
every single week of using everything
and writing these meticulous friction
logs that then informs what are we
working on next. Uh, of course, we want
to hear from our actual users as well.
Um, just such an incredible tool and
that's another place where if you write
those things and send them around, you
can really kind of highlight what is
good enough and what the bar is in the
product. One thing that Stripe is really
famous for is there's this uh you know
many nines of reliability just this
really legendary engineering feat and
you know of course there's these
engineering blog posts out there that
you know people can read if they're
curious how it's done but what I wanted
to ask you as the CTO of Stripe was what
are the intentional
engineering culture changes that kind of
enable that type of reliability? By the
way, the team during my tenure, I think
we got Stripe to more than five nines of
reliability. I hear that last quarter
they achieved six nines. That is an
incredible feat. So, you know, kudos to
everyone there who's working on
reliability. Um, and for a business like
Stripe, it really matters. You know,
every every second of downtime is like
huge dollar losses in the behalf of
businesses and they've got it like into
like very very um minimal amounts of
time in the year. Um it starts with
being incredibly intentional. Um as you
kind of correctly called out at Stripe,
we had a a really amazing and difficult
but you know ultimately incredibly
fulfilling year in 2020 which is
obviously with the pandemic suddenly
there was a huge desire for a lot of
offline business to go online. Um and so
we ended up being in a state where our
systems were scaling much faster than we
um had ever imagined. And against that
backdrop, uh we knew that we had to kind
of really raise the bar on reliability
in order to make sure that we were doing
a stellar job of serving those
businesses. Um so it really mattered for
the business, but it was actually not
something that the engineering org had
been kind of wired for before. There
certainly been periods where like this
is a emergency, let's jump in and fix
it. But earlier in that company's uh you
know life, we've been very focused on
let's make sure that we can find product
market fit for all the things that
matter for our users, which I think was
the right thing to do. But at scale,
reliability really mattered. So it
actually was mostly a kind of like
cultural change um that was important to
realize in order to to pull this off.
And as you said, there's a lot written
about this. So I won't go into too much
detail, but for me it started with being
intentional and then trying to give
every team the tools to actually think
about this in a scientific way so that
they could make the right trade-offs
between feature work that they would do
and work they would do for reliability.
Um so we did that by introducing this
ops review that I've already mentioned
with also a nested set of systems and
meetings that with a lot of tools to
provide data and then uh kind of
repeating uh opportunities to look at
those data and decide what do we want to
do about this uh in order to make it
better. So it really is like get a lot
of conviction that it matters and then
set up a repeatable system that causes
everyone to be able to have the right
input and then look at it often enough
to take the right action. Um the other
thing that is you know really awesome
about that period of time at Stripe is
that all of that progress was made
against the backdrop also of just
massive improvement in other
infrastructure traits because we started
measuring everything in a very
systematic way and bubbling it up to a
lot of a lot of people across the org.
We were able to start making a lot of
progress on not just reliability but
things like efficiency uh and
performance as well. So it was um it was
a really special time. Reliability is um
it's not free. There's it comes with
cost in terms of you know additional
machines for redundancy but also there's
a lot of overhead and probably you know
slowing things down you know let's do
more diff reviews let's have uh incident
reviews let's really make sure that if
it's touching a risky code path we go a
little slower.
>> Yeah.
>> Did you ever at Stripe think is it too
reliable and is it worth that tradeoff
in cost?
>> Yeah. First of all, I think like on face
value that makes sense. Um, you would
think, oh yeah, you need to run way more
machines to be reliable. Uh, in actual
fact that Stripe, we pulled off the
change that I just described while
making the system significantly more
efficient as well. Um, I think so I'm
not necessarily talking about Stripe
here, just like industrywide. They're
kind of two reasons that systems can be
unreliable,
at least two. One is, um, you're trying
to serve more demand than you have
capacity for. Um and there you might
decide to like overprovision things in
order to to make it work well. Um and it
it also may be that you haven't like
invested enough in kind of gradual
degradation and partial um you know
serving you know partial availability
and so forth. So that's that's one
reason. The other reason is just like
when making changes, there are not
enough guard rails or systems to prevent
things that engineers were trying to do
legitimately to improve the product to
have them like break stuff in the
system. And if you find yourself here,
then you have to think a lot about
things like overprovisioning. If you
find yourself here, it's actually a
completely different set of things that
you do in order to fix that. So, one of
the things that we were able to invest a
lot in at Stripe was having a huge
amount of infrastructure for automated
testing. Um, and yes, there were periods
of time where we said, "Hey, let's have
more reviews or whatever." But then by
investing in what are our systems to
have lots of tests and have gradual
deployment of changes, um, it actually
enabled the entire org to go faster. So,
I actually think that the the
industry-wide lesson I would take from
the experience at Stripe is how can we
have great automated testing and how can
we have really good gradual deployment
of changes where failures are detected
before they are critical. Um, and that
goes for like changes that you're making
in code, changes you're making in data,
changes you're making when you flip
feature flags for users. All of these
things matter. And if you start paying
attention to what's causing problems and
then asking you know five W's behind
them to see what what changes can we
make um I think you'll find that you can
cover enormous ground and actually you
know in this particular case we ended up
not having to make that many trade-offs
in terms of productivity and certainly
not in terms of efficiency. Uh so it
really all was about the right systems
for paying attention to the right data
and the right mechanisms for gradual
deployment of changes so that we would
detect failures earlier. And that meant
that we could have this amazing
environment where every engineer as they
you know if you merge a change to main
it was going to production like pretty
much directly the same day through a
kind of very uh deliberate set of
gradual uh release processes all fully
automated. Um and that's a cool
environment to work in. This is now
quite popular in the industry and
certainly it's how we work at at my
company today. Um, but when I worked at
Google, you didn't get to ship directly
to production. You um you merge your
change and then like maybe every two
weeks someone would take the time to to
like cut a release branch, test it,
sometimes a lot manually, uh fix up some
of the rough edges with some cherry
picks and then that would go to
production. It would sit there and not
change for two weeks. So if you were an
engineer writing a change, you know, on
day one you'd merge your change. maybe
up to two weeks later, someone would try
to release it to production and then it
would sit in production for another two
weeks. So, it was like often a month
between making your change and it being
like fully live. It's really hard to
iterate in that environment. It's so
much more fun when you can make a change
in the same day you can show it to your
friends in the product like so cool and
your and your co-workers. And that kind
of enabling rapid iteration like that
was a lot of how I like to think about
the right way to set up engineering
systems.
>> I see. So, if I'm understanding, you're
you're saying that with the right
investments in shifting left, so
catching regressions earlier,
>> you don't even you don't make that
trade-off between d-risking. You
actually can move fast and be safe.
>> That's right. Um, there's a good book
called Accelerate by Nicole Forsrren,
which touches on a lot of this. Not not
quite all of it, but a lot of it. So, I
recommend that book. One of the last
things on Stripe is uh Stripe was very
well known for the engineering talent
and I'm curious what are the material
actions that the company would take to
to hire such strong engineers. I think
the first thing that's important to know
about Stripe is um we had a lot of
amazing engineers
that actually wanted to work at Stripe
and would reach out to us and usually
the reason for that was that they had a
great experience with Stripe's product.
At the core of Stripe's product, there
are many different ways you can use it,
but the core is a developer platform. Um
I think it has a deserved reputation for
having some of the best documentation in
the industry. By the way, there we
considered building the docs part of
building the product. So it wasn't
something that a separate team worked
on. The product teams work on that. The
APIs are designed nicely. We took real
pride in the presentation of both the
product experiences and the marketing
page and so forth. So to some extent
like ship a great product and then
people will want to come work on it and
that that that matters a ton. Of course
we also had to make sure that we were um
evaluating people in the right way. At
the time that I was joining Stripe, the
industry was still doing a lot of
whiteboard interviews. You know, you'll
write code on a whiteboard during an
engineering interview. Certainly, all
the interviews I did before Stripe were
like that. And we believed and believe
today uh that that's actually like not a
great way of simulating what it's like
to see a real an engineer do work. So at
Stripe, we designed an interview process
where folks would actually be on a
laptop with all the tools that they were
used to having um and pair program with
an interviewer um and we try to give the
most kind of realistic experience of
work that we could. The programming
exercises were very deliberately
designed um uh in order to make sure
that we were selecting for folks that
wanted to be meticulous in their craft
that did have the core uh engineering
and design and and kind of inquisitive
skills to go and find the right things
that they needed to work on. Um and I
think that's a big part of how we uh
were able to maintain that talent bar
over many years.
One of the common things I hear about le
code and why it's used at the largest
companies is that to do what you did at
Stripe at scale is uh challenging you
know maintaining those people are going
to probably leak those questions about
that.
>> So how did how did Stripe do it
successfully because Stripe was a is a
very
>> I'm not going to lie it was hard work.
Um it is the case that interview
questions get leaked online. Um, and you
know, as soon as that happens, you need
a new interview question because you
want to make sure that you're fairly
assessing people and like getting a real
read, not you know, the people who
search for it on Google beforehand. Um,
so it's hard work. Um, there were a
decent number of engineers at Stripe
that were very passionate about this and
they also did a good job of kind of
getting other people passionate about
it. Um, and so it was a volunteer effort
to build those interview questions. It's
important I think as leaders and
managers to make sure that folks that
contribute to those kind of efforts are
recognized. Um so for instance I would
get up at engineering all hands and like
say thank you to the folks that have
done this. Honestly it contributed to
their advancement in the org. You had to
get your core work done really well but
if you're doing things like that that
was also really valuable and it really
just came from like actually caring
about it. So, if you tell me that Meta
or Google don't have the resources to
build good engineering interviews, I
don't believe you. I, you know, they
could totally do this if they wanted to,
it's really just a case of like a
revealed preference of how much they
care about it. By the way, both amazing
companies. I'm not I'm not criticizing
them, but uh I think if you really care
about something like this, it's possible
to apply the hard work to make it work
well. Earlier you you mentioned you know
what Stripe did to draw in the talent
even preassessment and it sounded like
you were saying that if you want to
attract excellent people build something
that's excellent. Is is that right?
>> It's probably neither necessary nor
sufficient. Like I think you can
probably attract great people to work on
a thing that's not great if you like pay
them beyond market or whatever. But
people are really excited to come and
work on something that is like
demonstrably awesome. So I'd much rather
do that than the uh the counterfactual.
Um and then is it sufficient? No. Like
it also has to be clear that you can um
you can you know learn a lot you know
advance your own career goals uh be
surrounded by people that you're going
to to to want to spend th those you know
precious hours of your life with. So, I
think it's neither necessary nor
sufficient, but it certainly goes a long
way.
>> As the CTO of Stripe, you had proximity
to Stripe's leadership team, and I'd
love to hear what are the things that
you learned from such talented people.
>> Yeah. So, I mean, I've I've alluded to
many of these along the way in this
conversation, but I think the thing that
I learned most from my friends and peers
on the leadership team was the value of
thinking from first principles. So I
would also say I was not very good at
this when I joined. Um at Google in
particular, you know, that company
invented a lot of the ways of working in
our industry back then and today and it
was very effective. You know, what an
amazing business, great products. So
when I was at Google, I would often be
like, well, we got to do this thing. How
did we do it last time? And we'll just
use that again. Um when I came to Stripe
um it was a very constant refrain and
kind of way of framing things that when
we had when we were faced with a problem
that we needed to solve we wouldn't just
say how did we solve it last time we
would say from first principles what is
actually going on here can we deeply
understand the dynamics and how can we
figure out what to do and another way of
thinking from first principles was to go
and ask people at multiple external
companies how they'd handled similar
problems before and then triangulate on
the right solution and that was really
eye opening for me. Uh it's definitely
something I try to continue to do today
and it was quite a different way of
working. Again, you know, we want to
solve a problem. Let's take time to go
and talk to four people at other
companies that have seen something like
this before. That could sound very slow,
but if you're applying that in the most
consequential places, it's amazing how
much you can benefit from multiple
perspectives and then reason from first
principles about the right way to move
forward. It sounds like you're saying it
it is a is a useful tool but not in
every single place because also I I mean
at this point in your career you have
seen so many patterns and you have had
successes that maybe sometimes worth
shortcutting um and using the
experience. Yeah, I think it's actually
remarkable
how frequently it does benefit to take a
quick step back and think from first
principles and actually check yourself
and say you think you've seen this
before but have you? Um and then you
know maybe 80% of the time it's like
yeah this is the thing I've seen before
go do but 20% of the time it's like oh
this is subtly different let me go and
see if I can get some other opinions.
Um, but you're right. It's not a tool to
be used in every single thing every day.
Otherwise, everything would grind to a
halt.
>> Coming away from Stripe, I saw you
recently left to start your current
company, which is Dev Agents. And I
would love to hear more about what the
company's building. And maybe we can
start with the story behind you leaving
Stripe and wanting to build this.
>> Sure. We're building this new company,
Dev Agents. We are focused on building a
platform. We call it a next generation
operating system uh to make it possible
for AI agents and agentic apps to work
for everyone for people. So we're
solving this problem for consumers.
There are a lot of companies out there
building uh agents and agent
infrastructure for enterprises and
that's a little bit of how I got got
into knowing that this was worth
solving. But we're specifically focused
on how can we apply this technology for
everyone and I think that's like super
exciting. Um, and also it means that
there's some really big problems to
solve. So I'll get back to those, but
let me tell you kind of how we got
started. So I mentioned earlier that I
started my career in the early days of
mobile. So I was working on smartphones
before they were a thing. And at that
time I got this like really deep
conviction that this technology mattered
and yet we had to solve you know
building by the way we kind of glossed
over this at Google. Um, I ended up
working as part of the Android team. Um
uh and Hugo, my co-founder, was part of
the very early product team on Android.
Uh Nicholas, who's my other co-founder,
also um designed a lot of the core, uh
mobile interfaces and then worked on
Chrome. So like we're kind of we're all
geeks for this um set of problems of
there's a technology and we have to
figure out how to invent the right
patterns to apply it for people at
scale. So back then it was so much fun
and so fulfilling to think about all the
ways that people were going to use this
technology and invent things like the
right permissions model, the right
application affordances like you know
how do you structure a UI? You know I
also worked on wearables, how do you get
the right UI onto a watch and so forth.
Um, and
at Stripe, um, as really powerful AI
models came out like GPT4, um, I had the
opportunity to apply them to problems
inside of the the business, uh, we were
building some of the world's first AI
agents. We didn't know to call them that
yet, but, you know, we were using an
LLM, having it perceive some data,
reason, and then take some action. So,
that was, you know, some of the first AI
agents. Um, and I got really obsessed
with the idea that this is as
breakthrough a technology as the early
days of mobile. Um, and I started
tinkering with this stuff in my free
time, nights and evenings, and realized
many of the problems that need to be
solved to make this work for people are
analogous to some of the problems that
we solved back then. Um, it's important
to have some place where agents and
agentic apps can exist, where they can
have context on the user. um where they
can work together where all those
problems around uh privacy and security
can be solved but in such a way that
real value is created for people and
then also it's a dual-sided marketplace
just like the early days of mobile. Um
we need a way for developers to have
access to a bunch of people. need a way
for people to have access to um all of
the experiences that have been crafted
for them by developers, builders,
creators. So that's what we're doing
here. The the inspiration really did
come directly from seeing that this is a
very similar moment uh to that early
stage of mobile. And yeah, it's been a
lot of fun. There is a lot of hard work
to do. Um but I'm excited about what
we're doing for uh for people at scale.
So I'm trying to understand what you
know what is the product here. So it
sounds like it's it's infrastructure
like a consumer would not know the the
words dev agent. It's that the consumer
would see this is my airline agent and
some developer built that and behind the
scenes they're using what you're
offering. We we are actually building
the platform that they will use to both
find those agents in agentic apps um and
use them. Dev agents is a company name.
It is not a product name. Um but they
certainly folks will eventually uh be
using you know the things that we build
as a way to access all of the
experiences that other people are
crafting. Um, and you know, as part of
that, we need to build all of the right
tools and experience for those
developers, crafters to build really
powerful and valuable agents. Um, and we
have to make them really accessible for
people. That's right.
>> The AI industry right now is like a war
zone. I mean, there's so much interest
and because there's so much interest,
there's so many people competing. I'm
curious, you know, how do you see
yourself out competing big names like
OpenAI who probably have interest in
this exact thing?
>> Yeah, absolutely. One of the things that
I think about a lot is in the early days
of mobile, we expected that the folks
that were going to like win the market
would be the Nokias and the Sony Ericens
of the world. They had, you know, the
first mover advantage. Um, and they did
a great job in the early days, but
ultimately what was necessary for mobile
to really work really well for people
was to invent whole new paradigms. So
like the iPhone had to come along and
Android had to come along. So I don't
think that it is a kind of foregone
conclusion that the folks that um are
kind of applying technology in any space
at the very beginning are the ones that
end up you know making the biggest
impact. Now I think there are amazing
companies out there that are going to
have a lot of impact. We happen to be
taking a very differentiated approach
from uh from any of the the the
experiences I see in the market right
now. I'm not quite ready to share what
it is. Um but you know you will see it
before too long and it is it's it's
pretty different and that's important
because I think we have figured out some
of the some of the kind of key
opportunities and constraints that um
are necessary to make this new
technology work for consumers at scale.
A big part of how we thought about this
is not like what is this company doing
or that company doing, but what do
people need? Like what are the use cases
that matter? Um how can we unlock kind
of compounding value if multiple
developers are building agents in this
environment? Um you know, how can they
work together in order to work really
well for people and that's what we're
kind of laser focused on. So it's pretty
different. Watch the space. Um, and uh,
in fact, we're we're right at the moment
now where um, if that sounds exciting
and you're the kind of person that likes
to tinker with new technology and build
things, we'd love to, uh, consider
having you as, uh, an early adopter of
the platform as a creator and developer
of these agents and agentic apps. So,
uh, if you go to sdsa.ai,
that stands for
slashdev/agents.ai/build,
I/build. That's where you can sign up to
be one of our uh creators in our early
access program. Across your career, you
started as an IC. You went all the way
up to some of the highest levels of of
leverage in these organizations and now
you're on a small team. And I'm curious,
what does the day-to-day look like now?
Like is it how different is it from that
first time you were a frontline manager?
I'd say that the way that I work today
is quite different from the very first
time I was a frontline manager. Mostly
because of just all the experience I've
had along the way and the lessons that
I've learned. So I am constantly trying
to apply all of the stuff that I talked
about in this conversation. You know,
I'm stepping onto the balcony to make
sure I'm looking at how everything's
working periodically. uh I put a lot
more energy into both preparing myself
for every week and and trying to make
sure that the team are prepared for what
are the most important things for us to
work on this week. Whereas, you know,
very early in my career, it was a lot
more kind of follow your nose and do
kind of the the most obvious next
immediate thing. And so quite profoundly
different is the is the short answer,
but also um there's so much that is
similar and you know this both feels uh
feels a little bit like home. uh and
also feels like a wonderful new
challenge. And you obviously mentioned
how competitive the AI industry is right
now. That is true. Um I I wouldn't want
to work on anything else like I really
strongly believe that this is a profound
leap forward in technology and I as a
technologist I couldn't imagine not
working on it. Uh it certainly is hard
work which is very rewarding but I think
we're creating a lot of type two fun
right now.
Um, coming to the end of the interview,
I want to do some career reflections
going over everything that you've done
so far. So, if you were to look back on
your your career kind of with this
retrospective lens, kind of like an
incident almost, you know, what would
you say went well, what do you think
didn't go well? Maybe we can talk
through that. So in terms of things that
went well, uh one, I do think that I was
very fortunate um in some of the very
early uh you know choices or kind of
things that I got thrown into. Finding
myself at Symbian, which has been
completely formative for the rest of
what I've done was honestly pretty
random. So uh I don't know what anyone
can take away from that, but um that
that definitely was very very useful. I
think for me I mentioned that the reason
I stayed so long at Google and you know
also kind of why I enjoyed quite a long
time at Stripe so much was focusing on
always making sure that I was learning.
I think that has been incredibly
important and valuable and I I have made
choices to move teams within companies
um specifically because I thought that
was an opportunity to learn things that
would put me outside of my comfort zone.
I mean an example of that I worked on
mobile at Google before Android. Um
there was then a weekend where I
remember it very clearly mobile search
there were more queries than desktop
search. That was like a real wake up
moment for the whole company. It was
like we got this little team on the side
building all this mobile stuff but now
look it's mainstream and we actually did
this really brave thing I think of like
deciding to disband our team and push it
out into all the rest of the company.
Um, and as someone who was working
across a bunch of stuff in mobile, the
default path for me would have been to
at that time go join the Android team. I
did later join the Android team. Uh, but
what I decided to do was I thought,
well, that's going to be that's cool.
Like I was already working on a bunch of
mo of of Android apps. I'd already had
the opportunity to inform some of the
kind of core of the operating system.
But I thought, hey, the best thing for
me to learn at Google right now is if I
go and work on ads because I had no idea
how Google made money. And so I did that
and it put me way outside of my comfort
zone. Um I was like already like
reasonably senior. Most people who were
in that org had kind of grown up in the
org. They knew everything. I had to
learn at a tremendous rate. But man, it
was awesome. I mean I now understand how
like all of those auction systems work
and uh I understand the publisher and
advertiser business model and so forth.
I I wouldn't know that if I hadn't taken
that leap. So focusing on always
learning I think is something that uh
has stood me in goodstead. What about
looking back? Is there anything you
regret where you thought, you know, I
could have changed that and that would
have been a lot better?
>> Yeah. Uh, I mean, look, there are a lot
of things that with the benefit of
hindsight, I would have done
differently. Hopefully, I've been fairly
transparent in that during this
conversation. I mean, I mentioned how I
think I was a pretty lousy manager at
the start because I was focusing on
helping people be happy rather than like
how do we get the most impact um out.
You know, when I was a very early stage
engineer, I didn't speak up in meetings
that often because I kind of assumed
that my manager and like their manager
like they kind of knew it all. They had
it all sorted out. And why do they want
to hear from me? I'm just like this, you
know, newbie. But actually, what you
realize as you go through your career is
the people who have the very most
context for everything going on are the
folks that are actually doing the
building at the one foot level. Right?
So in many of those meetings where I was
sitting there thinking I don't I think
they're wrong but I they must know
right. I knew because I was the one
doing the work. Um and of course you
know now that I have been in those rooms
as the more senior person like I really
wish I created a culture where people
would speak up right and so um just like
that that's maybe something that I would
try and take away is um mental model how
what they're thinking about they're hum
they're just humans everyone's just a
human they only know as much as any
human could possibly like pars into
their own brain and if you are the
expert and really know something assume
that they're wrong and speak up and um I
found that in the companies that I
worked at that is always rewarded and
it's something I seek to reward in in my
organizations as well. Obviously, I
don't want to give everyone bad advice.
If you're in an organization that kind
of patently does not reward that, like
maybe go work somewhere else. Uh but
most good companies work like that. And
I think that that that's something I
wish I'd known a little bit sooner
>> and is one way to know if a company's
like that is if the titles are less in
your face.
>> Yeah, I mean I don't think there's any
like one hard and fast rule for this. Um
but you know it's certainly the case
that you know Google back when I joined
most people if you joined at the actual
entry level which I did you got given a
job title uh but most people were given
this title which is member of technical
staff and the whole point there was
we're not going to say what your level
is in a publicly kind of discernable way
because we want people to listen to your
ideas not just because of like your your
title or who you are and I think that's
like a trait that's common to
organizations that work that way. Um,
it's not the only one. I think just if
you see people speaking up and making
good points and then they are listened
to and, you know, encouraged to speak up
again, that's probably another good
sign.
>> Well, I had no idea that early Google
also used that title cuz I I thought
well maybe the source was um Bell Labs
and
>> I think the source was Bell Labs. By the
way, it's amazing the kind of like
family tree of all the practices in our
industry. Um, I'm pretty certain that
Bell Labs was the progenitor. Um, but it
definitely was uh the way Google worked
when I joined Google, which was, you
know, 2005, 2006.
>> Is there a top recommendation for a book
that really impacted your career?
>> I'm sure you've heard this one before,
High Output Management by Andy Grove.
Um, so Andy Grove was the CEO at Intel.
And I just talked about like the family
tree of all the business practices in
our industry. It turns out that like
almost every way of working that I ran
into at Google uh and assumed that
Google had invented uh actually came
from Andy Grove. Uh so like OKRs are
there. He talks about how to do
efficient oneto ones etc. It's a really
short book. I read it on one flight. Um
and it's I mean it was a flight from
London to Mountain View. So you know
give yourself a few hours. It's like
interesting like it's a bit of a page
turner. Um, and so many of the practices
I'd seen at large actually come from
this book. And you know, there are
certainly some things in there which
probably don't make so much sense
anymore, but as a as a moment that made
me think differently about how to like
run everything I do at work, reading
that book was was pretty pivotal.
>> Um, habits are very powerful, especially
they they compound over time. I'm
curious, is there any habit that you
took with you throughout your career
that really had an impact?
>> There definitely is one. So, for the
longest time, I would just kind of do
whatever was coming at me. Like, I'd get
email and I'd like work on it. Or I'd
have someone would put a thing on my
calendar and I'd do it. Or I'd have all
of the oneto ones with my team
scheduled. So, I knew that like I'm
going to Brian's onetoone tomorrow, so I
should work on that. So, like my
calendar and my inbox kind of like ruled
me. And I was setting some goals and so
forth, but they kind of ruled me. And I
realized that's like completely
backwards. If you want to if you want to
make something happen, you should just
like figure out how to make it happen
and go do those things. So, a practice
that I started many years ago, certainly
during my time at Google, was I started
writing a essentially a to-do list for
myself for every week. I found that a
week is the right level of granularity.
And so on Sunday nights, I would just
take a moment to think what if I if I
have a great week this week, what did I
get done? And I write those things down.
Um, and I actually the the doc that I
put these in, uh, I call it my rocket
doc. Like I gave it the emoji title of a
rocket as soon as it Google Doc
supported emojis. And that's kind of
like the the energy I want out of that
thing. And then, you know, during the
week, that is my that's the thing I come
back to all the time. So, I'm like, am I
what am I supposed to do next? Don't go
to your inbox. Don't go to your
calendar. Go to the Rocket Dog. Um, that
has been really great. So, being
deliberate about what to work on. Um,
later. So you know I started that when I
was you know just me with you know folks
on my team. Uh much later I had the the
privilege of having um a couple of
tremendous executive assistants that
would help me. Um and something that was
a real kind of cheat code I guess was
I'd share that doc with them and then
I'd say like our collective goal is to
make sure I actually spend my time on
this stuff this week. So, you know, by
middle of the day, Tuesday, um, uh, my
EA would ping me on Slack or whatever,
depending where I was working, um, and
say like, "How are we doing against
these things?" and start chasing me to
do the stuff that I wanted to do. It was
amazing. Um, and they could like help
make sure that I spent my calendar and
so forth on that as well. So, that habit
is pretty important. I want to mention
one other habit as well. Um, exercise is
really important. I realized that every
time I was finding myself being like
pretty grumpy at work and a bit unhappy
just because I'd like forgotten that you
have to exercise, it makes endorphins.
It makes you feel good. So like if
you're ever like in a funk at work, just
like make sure that you're like working
out a few times a week. Um it's amazing
how often that was the thing that I just
had to do to keep myself in an even
keel. And the last question that I want
to ask you is, you know, if you could go
back to yourself when you just graduated
from college and you were right about to
enter the industry and you could give
yourself some advice, what would you
say?
It's a really good question.
I think I'd repeat that piece of advice,
which is when you're in that moment
where you think where you know a thing
and you assume that it's because you're,
you know, not the person who's in
charge, just speak up. I think good
things happen and I think that um uh if
I done it a bit more, even more good
things would have happened in in the the
spots that I was in.
>> Well, thank you so much for your time,
David. I really appreciate it. This was
really interesting conversation. Um, now
is your opportunity if you want to, you
know, tell the audience anything and you
can go ahead and speak.
>> We're building a really small talent
dens team here at Dev Agents. So, there
aren't a lot of spots for for folks to
join. If you think that you really are
excited about this and you're one of
those people, you're welcome to send me
an email. We can put my email address in
your show notes. Um, but in particular,
if you're someone who'd like to tinker
with our platform and build uh some new
and exciting Agentic apps and
experiences for people, sdsa.ai/build.
Um, we'd love to see if we can get you
in in the early access program.
>> All right. Thanks so much. Really
appreciate your time.
>> Thanks a lot.
>> Thanks for listening to the podcast. I
don't sell anything or do sponsorships,
but if you want to help out with the
podcast, you can support by engaging
with the content on YouTube or on
Spotify if you want to drop a review,
that'll be super helpful. And if there's
any guests that you want to bring on to,
please let me know. I feel like sourcing
very senior IC's, there's no wellstudied
list out there on Google that I can just
search this up. So, if there's someone
in your org or at your company who you
really look up to and you want to hear
their career story, let me know and I'll
reach out to them.